Guide to the Ujamaa Records SC1127
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ujamaa records
circa 1970-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ujamaa (Stanford University)
SC1127
16 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
16 linear feet (10 boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative materials, newspaper clippings, photographs, posters, and audiovisual materials created and/or collected by the Ujamaa theme dormitory at Stanford University. These materials document the administration and history of the theme house from the 1970s to 2012.
Acquisition Information
The materials were transferred from the Ujamaa House to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2012.
Dormitories -- California -- Stanford.; African American college students; Stanford University -- History.; Ujamaa (Stanford University)
- Administrative Records
  - Programs (performance information) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Community and Health Advisory (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Fund (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ujamaa Staff Binder, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Imani Class of 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Organization Handbooks (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Imani 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mounted document copies (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History 299H (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Grape Policy Committee (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Residential Staff Resources from ResEd (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Resources - Courses and Community Involvement (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Froshbooks (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - BSU Committee on Ujamaa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ujamaa House Info (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Role of Selectivity (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History of Ujamaa (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - EPA Incorporation (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Misc Administrative (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Real News general info (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alex Haley 1986 article (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Angela Davis, 1983 DAILY article (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Real News Spr 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Campus Report 1988 november (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - RA Recruitment of students of color (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings - originals (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Real News 1988 original (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - random news clippings (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - News you can use: what every frosh should know 1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Assorted newsprint publications (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Pipeline (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Community Events - Publicized or Sponsored by Ujamaa (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Grapevine 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ethnic/Racial groups on campus (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Grapevine 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Grapevine 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Grapevine 1970's (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Grapevine 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - BCSC & Centro Clerical Staff Increase (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Budget Proposals BCSC & Centro (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Stanford Maps (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - BLM Administrative Staff (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faye Knox Correspondence 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Thom Massey Correspondence 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Keith Naylor Correspondence 1980-83 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Henry Organ Correspondence 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minority Report 1973. Dean of Student Affairs (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Asian American Community (Brochure/Flyer) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Black Presence at Stanford (Flyer) Donald Kennedy, Speech (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford American Indian Organization (SAIO) POWOW Fundraising, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minority Affairs at Stanford report requested by F Knox (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Education Bill of Rights, Minority Organizations. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Forum on Racism & Random Minority Related Issues (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chicano/Latino Community, 1975-85 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Office of the Assistant to the President for Black Affairs (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dean Search Info. Directory of Black Resources (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Assistant Dean Search applications (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Related Issues & Paperwork, etc. Black Caucus. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Black Caucus 1984 at Santa Clara (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - clippings (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ujamaa and BSU (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Black Community Services Center (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Black Liberation Month (BLM) Essay Contest (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The New Day (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondences, Agendas. Black Caucus 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence & Agendas. Black Caucus 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Affirmative Action, Staff Employment. Black Caucus 1974-76 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General Info. Black Caucus 1976-77 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - BCSC directors: Knox & Archuletta (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Black Activities Center (BAC) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Black Student Volunteer Center (BSVC) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Black House Renovations (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Draft - Major Responsibility Areas 81-82 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Program funds & proposals BCSC (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Stanford Black Alumni Reunion, BVSO (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Spring Retreat, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Related Random Stuff BCSC (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - General Administrative Staff (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence BCSC1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Orientation & BROC BCSC (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Intern Training Program BCSC (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Policy Board/BCSC Meeting Memorandum (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Black Media Workshop. Spr 1982, F. Knox (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Constitution, Goals & History BCSC (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Newsletter BCSC 1980-81 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Centennial Press Packet, 1987 Rainbow Coalition (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Africa, S. Africa, Tutu (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Toward a More Adequate Administrative Structure. Glenn Jordan/BCSC (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jean Fetter, Minority Admissions (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Protests, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Protest/pres. office takeover may-oct 1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Police brutality, harassment, racism, ethnocentrism, free speech (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Status of Minorities (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - University Committee on Minority Issues (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Chicano related issues (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Real News 1988 October (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - ethnic studies/W. CIV debate (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - A/BSSA 1989 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - More Police brutality & racism (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Controversial Cartoons, Philip Chalk (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - The Shockley Incident 1983-4 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Police Report, 1982 Nil Henderson (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Jesse Jackson, 1988 campaign letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Western Culture/CIV Debate (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Articles - Photocopies (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - African & African American Studies (AAAS) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Funding proposals. OSA, FAye Knox (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters OSA (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Black PreBus & Business BVSO's (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Flyers (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Greek System *minority interests (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Rhythms" KZSU, 1979, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Publications (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Omega Foundation BVSO (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Black Seniors Organization, 1982 BVSO (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Kusema Ukweli / Sub-committee of BSU BVSO (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - AKA History Competition BVSO (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Gospel Choir (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Black Student Graduate Association (BSGA) BVSO (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - SBSE & NSBE BVSO (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha BVSO (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - AMEN BVSO (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Black Performing Arts BVSO (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Omega Psi Phi BVSO (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Black Community Programming (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Beethoven and Hippocrates flyer 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Black Baccalaureate letter from B. Bowman (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Youth Outreach Day 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Programming related BCSC (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Activities, Documentation, and Programming Training (Adapt) / BCSC (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Jazz Cafe" / Mirrilees funding proposal (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Black Arts Festival 1981 & 1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Black Leaders Conference 1985 Stanford (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ujamaa Misc. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - MLK related (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. (MLK) general information (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Black on Black (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Black Students at Stanford (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - General Information: Black Volunteer Service Organization (BVSO) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Interactive Mentoring: African American Networking Initiative (IMAANI) BVSO (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Black Baccalaureate 1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - The Black Lart 1980 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Justice & Hope, 1989 Steve Phillips / BSU (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Editorials, letters, columns (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Black Academic/Social Support Network (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Stanford African Students Association (SOSA) BVSO (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Black PreMed Organization BVSO (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lively Arts at Stanford (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - WATU (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Stanford out of South Africa (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Stanford Black Pre-Law Society (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1969 Bookstore Attack (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - BLM related (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Kwanzaa 80 page book (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Louis Jackson BSU Association (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Louis Jackson events, 1989 (see BSU folder) (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - BSU Related Articles (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - BSU information sheet (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Black Student Union (BSU) BVSO (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Ujamaa event planning (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Ujamaa Journal, 1983, 1986-87 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Hardware Research 1996 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Background info, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Undated catalogue, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - layouts, floor plans. Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - alumni, faculty, board of trustees, rosters (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Olivo-Magnolia - Black Cultural Center (UJ) 1976 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - random copies, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - BCL info, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - minutes, notes. Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Committee Members, Ujamaa Archives (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Policies Pertaining to Residentially Related Selective Groups. Office of Dean of Student Affairs. (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Paperwork. Ujamaa. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Founding documents. Ujamaa Archives (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - related random shit. Ujamaa (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Britts Paperwork. Ujamaa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - RF Selections: Keith Calhoun Ujamaa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - House Awards. Ujamaa (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - TA information. Ujamaa (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1986 Financial Statement. Club Uj. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Acquisition Guidelines. Ujamaa Archives 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Constitution. Ujamaa Archives (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Proposal for Continuation of Theme Houses. Britts, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Theme House Clippings, editorials (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Academics (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - RF Materials (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Last Year Info (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Current File (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - New Students (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - BCSC Calendar 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - TCB - 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - BSU Convocation 2004 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Ujamaa Journal, Vol. 1, No. 5 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - History of Ujamaa (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate Advising Center - Group 4 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - BSU Rally (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Ujamaa Relocation Update (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Black Community Calendar 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - BSU pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Jam Pac'd Notebook (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Jam Pac'd Loose Leaves (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Jam Pac'd Binder (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - El Camino Hospital (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Jam Pac'd Administrative (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Jam Pac'd Business (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - NSBE Misc (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Archives (Completed Events/Etc.) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - SSE Capital Group (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Nationals Info (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - SBSE - Treasurer (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Region 6 Leadership Conference (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Regional Leadership Conference (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - ASSU Account (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Stanford Fund (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - E-Board Meetings (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - NSBE Treasurer (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Financial Zone Functional - Powerpoint Slides (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - NSBE Annual Convention, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - SBSE Auction 2001 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Northern Camping Conference Proposal (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - ASSU (Box 4, Folder 48)
- News Clippings
  - Flat Box of Assorted Clippings and Newspapers, incl. Campus Reports, Dailies, and Real News. (Box 6)
  - Flat Box of Assorted Clippings and Newspapers (Box 7)
  - Flat Box of Assorted Clippings and Newspapers (Box 8)
- Photographs, photo albums
  - Ujamaa Expressions, Volume 1. Album., 1986-87 (Box 5, Item 1)
  - Unlabelled blue photograph album (Box 5, Item 2)
  - BSU, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Item 3)
  - Ujamaa Journal, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Stanford Summer Academy. Album., 1989 (Box 5, Item 4)
  - Misc. Photos - unlabelled (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Loose, Unidentified Photos - 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Loose, Unidentified Photos - 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Loose, Unidentified Photos - 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Loose, Unidentified Photos - Negatives (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Flyers (Box 5)
- Posters
  - Flat Box of Assorted Posters and Fliers (Box 9)
- Audiovisual materials
  - Jam Pac'd Spring Show, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Jam Pac'd Spring Show, 2003; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10, Item 2)
  - Jam Pac'd Highlight Long, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10, Item 3)
  - BAD BOYS Soundtrack, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10, Item 4)
  - Unlabelled, colored blue on one side., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10, Item 5)
  - Zip Disk. Unlabelled., 1 computer media (Box 10, Item 6)
  - Zip Disk. Unlabelled., 1 computer media (Box 10, Item 7)
  - Zip Disk. Unlabelled., 1 computer media (Box 10, Item 8)
  - Treasurer Files Mike, 1 optical disc(s) (cd-r) (Box 10, Item 9)
  - E-Learning AIM, Avant-Projet., 1 optical disc(s) (cd-r) (Box 10, Item 10)
  - Unlabelled., 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 10, Item 11)
  - Unlabelled., 0 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 10, Item 12)
  - Carroll, Grace interview, 2011; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Nunn, Ken interview, 2011; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Ogletree, Charles interview, 2011; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Toliver, Derek interview, 2011; 3 computer file(s) (mp3)